Amairani Rosario

amairanirosario22@gmail.com | 407-873-2653

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/amairani-rosario/ | GitHub: http://github.com/AmairaniR

Portfolio: https://amairanir.github.io/Portfolio-Website/

Summary

Five years of experience in foreign languages (English, Spanish, French, Italian) and education, gaining valuable transferable skills in leadership, strategic planning, and presentation and communication. Strong track record of quickly adapting in new and complex situations. Eager to leverage a diverse range of talents in data science, foreign languages, and education in a new and engaging professional setting. Committed to lifelong learning and personal development.

Technical Skills

Excel, Git, VBA, Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, APIs, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Plotly, Tableau, R, ETL, Flask, MongoDB, Bootstrap, Spark, NLP, AWS, Supervised Machine Learning, Scikit-Learn, Imbalanced-Learn, Neural Networks, TensorFlow, Unsupervised Machine Learning, KMeans, Web Scraping, D3, Leaflet, Microsoft Office Suite, Google Suite

Project Experience

Neural Network Charity Analysis | GitHub Repo: https://github.com/AmairaniR/Neural_Network_Charity_Analysis

- Implemented a deep learning neural network binary classifier using TensorFlow capable of predicting whether applicants will be successful if funded by a non-profit organization.
- Applied optimization techniques (i.e. KerasTuner) to the initial model to reach the target predictive accuracy.

School Districts Analysis | GitHub Repo: https://github.com/AmairaniR/school-districts-analysis

 Aggregated the standardized reading and math test scores for schools in a district using Python and Pandas in Jupyter Notebook to establish trends in school performance to help decide budget allotments for the fiscal year.

Amazon Vine Analysis | GitHub Repo: https://github.com/AmairaniR/Amazon_Vine_Analysis

- Optimized the marketing efforts of Amazon's book reviews by using PySpark to extract the data, transform it, and connect it to an AWS RDS instance.
- Loaded the transformed data into PgAdmin using PostgreSQL to create the tables.
- Determined the presence of bias, using Python, towards favorable reviews from vine members, who are required to publish a review, versus non-vine members.

MechaCar Statistical Analysis | Github Repo: https://github.com/AmairaniR/MechaCar_Statistical_Analysis

- Performed retrospective analysis of historical data, analytical verification and validation of current automotive specifications, and study design of future product testing using statistical programming with R to facilitate the decision-making process for the manufacturing team.
- Statistical tests performed: linear regression, summary statistics, and t-tests

Professional Experience

French Teacher - Parental Leave Subtitute

The Lawrenceville School Lawrenceville, NJ

January 2022 – June 2022

- Taught two sections of French 1, three sections of French 2, and an honors class for grades 9 to 12 to classes of 5 to 12 students
- Mentored a teaching assistant in effective strategies for teaching the French 1 curriculum, guiding other students to better language comprehension, and leading individual small group sessions
- Advised senior students through all stages of their final projects, providing feedback and other resources for successful completion

Research Assistant

September 2020 - May 2021

Princeton University Princeton, NJ

- Analyzed the documents and images in Jacques Derrida's digitized seminars to confirm that all images were in numerical and logical order
- Reported any discrepancies in the images and content to the director through Microsoft Excel
- Collaborated with the director and other research assistants on how to assemble and present this future online archive to the public

Teaching Assistant/Instructor of Record

August 2018 – May 2020

University of Illinois at Chicago Chicago, IL

- Taught French and Francophone grammar, culture, and literature both in-class and online to classes of 20 to 25 students, three sections of level 101, and three sections of level 103
- Developed the curriculum and prepared daily lesson plans including objectives, explanations, activities, and assessments to improve reading, written, oral, aural proficiency in the target language
- Managed student and departmental communication, including grades and announcements, through Blackboard, Google Applications, and Microsoft Office Suite

Education

Certificate in Data Analytics. <i>Columbia University</i> New York, NY Master of Arts in French. <i>University of Illinois at Chicago</i> Chicago, IL Bachelor of Arts in French. <i>Florida State University</i> Tallahassee, FL	2022 2020 2017
---	----------------------

Languages: Fluent in English, Spanish, and French. Reading knowledge in Italian.